These Foreign-only subtitles ver. 2025-08 were created by ZoowlCZ.
[Sindarin] ♫ Estel, le iôn adar lín... ♫
[English] ♫ Hope, you are your father’s son... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ ... û iôn naneth lín. ♫
[English] ♫ ... not your mother’s child. ♫
[Sindarin] Anirne hene beriad i chên lîn.
[English] She wanted to protect her child.
[Sindarin] Ned Imladris nauthant e le beriathar aen.
[English] She thought in Rivendell you would be safe.
[Quenya] ♫ I tuo, i macil... ♫
[English] ♫ The strength, The weapon... ♫
[Quenya] ♫ Astaldoron mauri... ♫
[English] ♫ The needs of the valiant... ♫
[Quenya] ♫ Nai túren... ♫
[English] ♫ Be it that victory... ♫
[Quenya] Cuiva nwalca Carnirassë!
[English] Wake up cruel Redhorn!
[Sindarin] Losto Caradhras, Sedho! Hodo!
[English] Sleep Redhorn, Be still! Lie Still!
[Sindarin] Nuitho i 'Ruith!
[English] Hold your Wrath!
[Quenya] Cuiva nwalca Carnirassë!
[English] Wake up cruel Redhorn!
[Quenya] Nai yarvaxëa rasselya...
[English] May your bloodstained horn...
[Quenya] ...taltuva ñotto-carinnar!
[English] ...fall upon enemy heads!
[Sindarin] Annon Edhellen edro hi ammen!
[English] Gate of the elves, open now for me!
[Sindarin] Fennas Nogothrim, lasto beth lammen.
[English] Doorway of the Dwarf-folk, listen to the word of my tongue.
[Quenya] Ando Eldarinwa...
[English] Gate of elves...
[Quenya] ...a lasta quettanya...
[English] ...listen to my word...
[Quenya] ...fenda casarinwa!
[English] ...threshold of dwarves!
[Sindarin] Mellon.
[English] Friend.
[Sindarin] ♫ Man ammen toltha i dann hen morn? ♫
[English] ♫ Who brings to us this token of darkness? ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ Si dannatha, nauva. ♫
[English] ♫ Will now fall, will be. ♫
[Quenya] ♫ Mel~ Melma nóren sina... ♫
[English] ♫ Love for this land... ♫
[Quenya] ♫ ...núra ala eäro núr. ♫
[English] ♫ ...greater than sea deeps. ♫
[Sindarin] Mae govannen, Legolas Thranduilion.
[English] Welcome, Legolas son of Thranduil.
[Sindarin] Govannas vîn gwennen le, Haldir o Lórien.
[English] Our fellowship stands in your debt, Haldir of Lórien.
[Sindarin] A Aragorn in Dúnedain...
[English] Oh, Aragorn of the Dúnedain...
[Sindarin] ...istannen le ammen.
[English] ...you are known to us.
[Sindarin] Boe ammen veriad lîn. Andelu i ven!
[English] We need your protection. The road is too dangerous!
[Sindarin] Merin le telim.
[English] I wish we may come with you.
[Sindarin] Boe ammen i dulu lîn!
[English] We need your support!
[Sindarin] Merin le telim.
[English] I wish we may come with you.
[Sindarin] Andelu i ven!
[English] The road is too dangerous!
[Quenya] ♫ Ela i cá ♫
[English] ♫ Behold the light! ♫
[Quenya] ♫ Nenya sina... ♫
[English] ♫ Nenya is this... ♫
[Quenya] ♫ ...corma úhátima... ♫
[English] ♫ ...ring unbreakable... ♫
[Quenya] ♫ ...i haryanye. ♫
[English] ♫ ...that I possess. ♫
[Sindarin chorus] ♫  In gwidh ristennin...  ♫
[English] ♫ The bonds cut... ♫
[Quenya solo] ♫  Ilfirin nairelma.  ♫
[English] ♫ Undying is our regret. ♫
[Sindarin chorus] ♫  ...i fae narchannen.  ♫
[English] ♫ ...the spirit broken. ♫
[Quenya solo] ♫  Nauva i nauva.  ♫
[English] ♫ What should be shall be. ♫
[Sindarin chorus] ♫  I Lach Anor ed...   ♫
[English] ♫ The Flame of Anor out... ♫
[Quenya solo] ♫  Ilfirin nairelma...  ♫
[English] ♫ Undying is our regret... ♫
[Sindarin chorus] ♫  ...ardhon gwannen.   ♫
[English] ♫ ...left this world. ♫
[Quenya solo] ♫  ...ar ullume nucuvalme.  ♫
[English] ♫ ...yet we will cast all away. ♫
[Sindarin chorus] ♫  Mithrandir, a Randir Vithren...  ♫
[English] ♫ Mithrandir, o Pilgrim Grey... ♫
[Sindarin chorus] ♫  ...ú-reniathach...  ♫
[English] ♫ ...you will not journey... ♫
[Quenya solo] ♫  Nauva i nauva.  ♫
[English] ♫ What should be shall be. ♫
[Sindarin chorus] ♫  ...i amar galen.  ♫
[English] ♫ ...the world green. ♫
[Quenya solo] ♫  Melme nóren sina...  ♫
[English] ♫ Love for this land... ♫
[Sindarin chorus] ♫  I reniad lín ne môr nuithannen.  ♫
[English] ♫ The journey of you in darkness stopped. ♫
[Quenya solo] ♫  Ilfirin nairelma...  ♫
[English] ♫ Undying is our regret... ♫
[Quenya solo] ♫  ...ar ullume nucuvalme.  ♫
[English] ♫ ...yet we will cast all away. ♫
[Quenya] ♫  Ai! Laurië lantar lassi súrinen.  ♫
[English] ♫ Alas! Like gold fall leaves in the wind. ♫
[Sindarin] Le aphadar aen.
[English] You are being tracked.
[Sindarin] Am meleth dîn...
[English] For her love...
[Sindarin] ...I ant e guil Arwen Undómiel pígatha.
[English] ...the gift of life of Arwen will fade.
[Sindarin] Aníron i e broniatha...
[English] I wish that she endures...
[Sindarin] ...Ad ae periatham athar i methid en-amar hen.
[English] ...even if we separate beyond the limits of this world.
[Sindarin] Aníron i e círatha na Valinor.
[English] I wish that she sails to Valinor.
[Quenya] Namárië.
[English] Farewell.
[Sindarin] Nadath nâ i moe cerich...
[English] There is much you have yet to do...
[Sindarin] ...dan...
[English] ...but...
[Sindarin] ...ú-'eveditham, Elessar.
[English] ...we shall not meet again, Elessar.
[Quenya] ♫  Et Eärello, Endorenna utúlien.  ♫
[English] ♫ Out of the Great Sea, to Middle-earth I am come. ♫
[Quenya] ♫  Sinome, maruvan, ar hildinyar.  ♫
[English] ♫ In this place, I will abide, and my heirs. ♫
[Black Speech] Akha...
[English] Here...
[Black Speech] ...ashi...
[English] ...only...
[Black Speech] ...gurum!
[English] ...death!
[Quenya] ♫  I tuo, i macil.  ♫
[English] ♫ The strength, The weapon. ♫